<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Biological Sciences Division</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<p>The Division of Biological Sciences encompasses a breadth of disciplines spanning all levels of organization and encompassing diverse organisms. With about 112 full-time faculty in two departments, the division offers a variety of programs that allow students to prepare for future careers in professional fields such as health sciences, veterinary medicine, biotechnology, environmental science, and academia. Undergraduate majors are encouraged to gain experience through <a href="http://research.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">independent research studies</a> by working closely with faculty in cutting-edge research using advanced technology. </p>
<h3>Programs in Biological Sciences</h3>
<p>To learn more about various biological programs and research projects in L&amp;S, visit the links below.</p>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2020-21/undergraduate/degree-programs/integrative-biology" target="_blank">Integrative Biology</a> (IB) emphasizes organismal, ecological and evolutionary biology with a broad comparative approach, including both plants and animals. Faculty members are also associated with three major research museums (Museum of Vertebrate Zoology, Museum of Paleontology and Herbaria), and several field research stations facilitate studies of behavior and marine, freshwater and terrestrial ecology. Students have access to all of these <a href="http://ib.berkeley.edu/research/facilities/" target="_blank">outstanding research facilities and collections</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2020-21/undergraduate/degree-programs/molecular-cell-biology/" target="_blank">Molecular and Cell Biology</a> (MCB) focuses on lower levels of organization with the divisions of genetics, genomics and development; neurobiology; cell and developmental biology; biochemistry, biophysics, and structural biology; and immunology and pathogenesis. Faculty members are also affiliated with independent research centers in neuroscience, cancer research, genomics, and aging. </p>
<p>A separate <a href="http://guide.berkeley.edu/2020-21/undergraduate/departments/physical-education/" target="_blank">Physical Education Program</a> (PhysEd) provides a wide range of physical activity classes as well as various lecture/laboratory courses. The activity offerings are designed to provide sequential instruction in classes such as aquatics, martial arts, dance, fitness, and sports. The <a href="http://pe.berkeley.edu/scubadiving/" target="_blank">Scientific Diving Program</a> which is included in PhysEd, may be used in undergraduate and graduate studies in biology and other disciplines.</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

