<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>

<title>Jewish Studies</title>


<text>
<![CDATA[  
<xml/>
  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext name="About the Program">
<![CDATA[
<p>The Designated Emphasis (DE) in Jewish Studies provides curricular and research resources for students who want to concentrate on Jewish Studies within their respective disciplines and have their work formally recognized in their degree designation. Designed to bring together faculty and students from different departments, the DE is administered by the Graduate Group in Jewish Studies and provides a unique context for rigorous cross-disciplinary research. Students applying to the DE must be prepared to integrate high-level research in Jewish Studies into their coursework, qualifying exam, and dissertation.</p>
<div>
<p>In keeping with UC Berkeley requirements for a Designated Emphasis, students must be admitted to the DE prior to taking their qualifying exams. We strongly encourage students to attend an informational meeting describing the program in their first year of graduate studies and formally apply for admission to the DE in their second year. The informational meeting takes place in the fall semester. The application deadline for the DE is in the fall semester (the exact date is announced each fall), with admission effective the following spring semester.</p>
</div>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext name="Admissions">
<![CDATA[
<p>To be admitted to the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies, an applicant must already be accepted into a PhD program at the University of California, Berkeley. For further information regarding admission to graduate programs at UC Berkeley, please see the <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/" target="_blank">Graduate Division's admissions website</a>.</p>
<p>Students will be required to fill out an application requesting admission to the DE, listing their prior preparation in the field, and their projected pathway through the program. In addition, they should submit a brief essay stating interests and reasons for applying, a CV, a writing sample, and a letter of recommendation from a faculty member in the student’s home department indicating why and how the student would benefit from the DE in Jewish Studies.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<designatedemphasisrequirementstext name="Designated Emphasis Requirements">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Normative time considerations</h3>
<p>Given the flexibility of the program, the completion of the DE will have no impact on Normative Time to degree.</p>
<h3>Requirements for Designation</h3>
<p>Students admitted to the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies must complete the following requirements before applying for their qualifying examination:</p>
<ol>
	<li>Students will be required to complete the course <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="JEWISH 290">JEWISH 290</span></span> Modern Jewish Scholarship: History and Practice, which will serve as the integrative course for the program regarding methodology and research skills. This course can be offered by any faculty member of the Graduate Group in the DE in Jewish Studies, and will likely rotate among core faculty. The course topics will thus vary in accordance with the specific expertise of individual faculty member(s). The course is worth 4 units. <br/>
	<br/>
	The course will be a combination of standard seminar format with shared readings and discussion, and individualized research and writing. The goal of this course is thus two-fold: to provide cohort cohesion and intellectual exchange across disciplines, and to provide the necessary intellectual background for top quality scholarship in the field of Jewish Studies. The course will have a strong practical component, including engagement with bibliographical resources and scholarly practices essential to doing work in the field of Jewish Studies. A final paper will be required. <br/>
	<br/>
	This course will be offered once every two years. The faculty members offering <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="JEWISH 290">JEWISH 290</span></span> are core members of the Graduate Group for the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies.</li>
	<li>Students in the DE will also complete three additional course electives related to Jewish Studies, which must be approved by the Graduate Group’s Curriculum Committee. These courses will support the interdisciplinary nature of the program with attention paid to the individual students' research interests. At least one of these courses must be taken in a department outside the student's major area of study or chronological period. In general, electives are graduate seminars, but an appropriate upper division undergraduate course may be approved if the student completes a graduate-level assignment for the course. One of the three electives may be fulfilled by repeating <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="JEWISH 290">JEWISH 290</span></span>, under the condition that the topic of this course differs from the previous <span class="sc_courseinline"><span class="code_bubble" data-code-bubble="JEWISH 290">JEWISH 290</span></span> they will have taken. Students will be provided a list of potential electives offered by the different departments sponsoring the DE. A student may petition to the advising committee to approve a course not on the established list.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Examination</h3>
<p>A member of the Graduate Group in Jewish Studies must be a formal member of the PhD qualifying examination committee. Under most circumstances, the graduate group member in the student’s home department will serve in this function. A member of the graduate group may also serve as the Academic Senate representative on the qualifying exam committee if not a faculty member of the student’s major. A Jewish Studies topic must be included as a subject on the qualifying examination. Satisfactory performance on the qualifying examination for the PhD will be judged according to the established rules in the student’s major program.</p>
<h3>Dissertation</h3>
<p>A member of the Graduate Group in Jewish Studies must be a formal member of the dissertation committee. The dissertation must relate to Jewish Studies (history, literature, culture, arts).</p>
<p>Faculty affiliated with the DE are Robert Alter, (Emeritus) Comparative Literature and Near Eastern Studies; Lilla Balint, German; Kenneth Bamberger, Boalt School of Law; Karen Barkey, Sociology; Isaac Bleaman, Linguistics; Robert Braun, Sociology;  Benjamin Brinner, Music; John Efron, History; Ronald Hendel, Near Eastern Studies; Ethan Katz, History; Chana Kronfeld, Comparative Literature and Near Eastern Studies; Ronit Stahl, History.</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequirementstext>
<coursestext name="Courses">
<![CDATA[
<h3>Jewish Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_jewish200" data-toggle="#cb_jewish200">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">JEWISH 200</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Topics in Jewish Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_jewish200">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2020, Spring 2019, Spring 2018<br/>
Graduate seminar will focus on specific areas or topics in Jewish studies through a combination of close reading of texts, student presentation, and informal lectures. Instructors and topics to vary semester to semester. Consult department website for updated course descriptions.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Advanced Topics in Jewish Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="564" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Three hours of Seminar per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Advanced Topics in Jewish Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_jewish290" data-toggle="#cb_jewish290">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">JEWISH 290</span> 
<span class="title">Modern Jewish Scholarship: History and Practice</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_jewish290">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Terms offered: Fall 2021, Spring 2021, Spring 2020<br/>
This seminar, specifically designed as the ‘integrative course’ for students pursuing the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies, will offer an in-depth introduction to some of the central trends and personalities in modern Jewish historiography. We will read (and read about) the founders of modern Jewish historiography, and then explore some contemporary trends in Jewish scholarship, according to the disciplinary affiliations of the students</span><span class="deschide"> in the class. Students will need to write a 5000-word article to complete the course, using a bibliography that includes Jewish Studies materials. A subject-relevant seminar paper from another course may be used to fulfill this requirement, subject to approval by Jewish Studies faculty.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Modern Jewish Scholarship: History and Practice:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="294" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> This is the required integrative course for doctoral students pursuing the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies. It is open to other doctoral students by permission of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-3 hours of seminar per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Two to three hours of seminar per week.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Efron</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Modern Jewish Scholarship: History and Practice:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_jewish296" data-toggle="#cb_jewish296">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">JEWISH 296</span> 
<span class="title">Jewish Studies DE Dissertation Research and Writing Credit</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_jewish296">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2011, Fall 2010, Spring 2010<br/>
The course is offered to graduate students in the Designated Emphasis (DE) in Jewish studies to provide course credit for conducting dissertation research and dissertation writing, only after the student has successfully advanced to candidacy.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Jewish Studies DE Dissertation Research and Writing Credit:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="820" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advancement to doctoral candidacy</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Twelve hour of Independent study per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Kronfeld</p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Jewish Studies DE Dissertation Research and Writing Credit:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_jewish299" data-toggle="#cb_jewish299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">JEWISH 299</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study and Research - Jewish Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 5 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_jewish299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2021, Spring 2014, Fall 2012<br/>
Topics and instructors will vary depending upon area of study. Special individual study for qualified graduate students only. Individual study and research, including fieldwork, in consultation with instructor on subject matter not covered in scheduled course offerings.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Study and Research - Jewish Studies:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="542" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-9 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Five hour of Independent study per week for 15 weeks. One and one-half to Nine hours of Independent study per week for 8 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Study and Research - Jewish Studies:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_jewish602" data-toggle="#cb_jewish602">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">JEWISH 602</span> 
<span class="title">Jewish Studies DE Exam Preparation</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_jewish602">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2012, Fall 2011, Spring 2011<br/>
The course is offered to graduate students in the Designated Emphasis (DE) in Jewish studies to provide opportunities for directed qualifying exam preparation prior to advancement to candidacy.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Jewish Studies DE Exam Preparation:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="267" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advancement to doctoral candidacy</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One to Twelve hour of Independent study per week for 15 weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Jewish Studies DE Exam Preparation:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Lila Balint, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Contemporary German literature and media, theories of the Contemporary, aesthetics and politics, transnationalism and translation, digital writing, European Jewish literatures, literary and cultural theory, theories of the novel.<br/><a href="https://german.berkeley.edu/people/lilla-balint/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kenneth A. Bamberger, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Technology, government regulations, corporate compliance.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/kenneth-bamberger"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Karen Barkey, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Comparative historical sociology, religion and politics, the politics of shared sacred sites .<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/karen-barkey"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Isaac Bleaman, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Sociolinguistics, language variation and change, sociophonetics, sociosyntax, corpus methods, language contact, multilingualism, language planning, language and ethnicity, Yiddish, Jewish language varieties.<br/><a href="https://jewishstudies.berkeley.edu/people/isaac-l-bleaman/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Isaac L. Bleaman, <i>Assistant Professor, Department of Linguistics</i>. </strong><br/><a href="https://www.isaacbleaman.com"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Robert Braun, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Altruism and social solidarity, comparative historical sociology, peace, war, and social conflict, political sociology, sociology of religion, social movements and collective behavior .<br/><a href="http://sociology.berkeley.edu/faculty/robert-braun"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Benjamin Brinner, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Indonesia, Java, Bali, Israel, musical memory, situated musical cognition, musical interaction, improvisation, gamelan, music and oral narrative.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14048"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John M. Efron, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cultural and social history of German Jewry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16360"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ronald Hendel, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Textual criticism, Hebrew bible, ancient Near Eastern religion and mythology, Northwest Semitic linguistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14832"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ethan Katz, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Jewish history, modern France, empire, Jewish-Muslim relations, secularism.<br/><a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/ethan-katz"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Chana Kronfeld, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Comparative literature, modernism, Hebrew, Yiddish, modern poetry, minor literatures, politics of literary history, feminist stylistics, intertextuality, translation studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14937"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Francesco Spagnolo, <i>Adjunct Associate Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ronit Stahl, <i>Assistant Professor, Department of History</i>. </strong>Faculty affiliate of the religious diversity cluster of the Haas Institute for a Fair and Inclusive Society.<br/><a href="https://history.berkeley.edu/ronit-y-stahl"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Rutie Adler, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Yael Chaver, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sarah Levin, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong><br/><a href="https://jewishstudies.berkeley.edu/people/sarah-levin/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Visiting Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Tomer Persico, <i>Visiting Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stephanie Rotem, <i>Visiting Assistant Professor</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Robert B. Alter, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Comparative literature, Near Eastern studies, 19th-century European and American novel, modernism, literary aspects of the bible, modern and biblical Hebrew literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14581"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Joan Bieder, <i>Senior Lecturer SOE Emeritus</i>. </strong>History of Jewish communities in South East Asia.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14443"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George Breslauer, <i>Faculty Director of the Magnes Collection of Jewish Art and Life</i>. </strong><br/><a href="https://jewishstudies.berkeley.edu/people/george-breslauer/"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Claude S. Fischer, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Social networks, American social history, technology, urban sociology, sociology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14671"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ann Swidler, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Religion, culture, Africa, AIDS, political sociology, theory, development, NGOs.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15516"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

